Cui Gongzi General Pei
Cui Gongzi 페이 장군
Visit the Chinese Valentine’s Day Lantern Festival
중국 발렌타인데이 등불 축제 방문
Make Yizhou Pengpi shine
Yizhou Pengpi를 빛나게 하세요
I am bold
나는 대담하다
Two of you please
두 명 부탁드립니다
Giving words to the Chinese Valentine’s Day wishing lantern
중국 발렌타인데이 소원등불에 말 전하기
請
請
Let’s write first
먼저 쓰자
Come and bring up the lamp
와서 램프를 가져와
Good words
좋은 말
Good meaning
좋은 의미
Okay, okay
알았어, 알았어
General Xiao Pei
샤오페이 장군
Let’s write something real
실제 글을 쓰자
Just write
그냥 쓰세요
Everyone marries a wife
모든 사람은 아내와 결혼합니다
Bring them all
모두 가져오세요
Let’s hold down the Western Army
서부군을 제압하자
They are all bachelors
그들은 모두 학사입니다
It’s like a bachelor’s army
총각부대같네요
Not even granted this wish
이 소원도 이루어지지 않았습니다
Good weather
좋은 날씨
Okay, okay
알았어, 알았어
Good
좋아요
What if this is at Laolan Pass
이것이 라오란 고개에 있다면
Make such a fire
불을 피우세요
Must roast a lamb
양고기를 구워야 합니다
Roasted until sizzling
지글지글해질 때까지 구웠어요
Not to mention how fragrant
얼마나 향기로운지는 말할 것도 없고
When I was little
어렸을 때
Grandma also often
할머니도 자주
Inside the fire
불 속
Give me roasted taro to eat
구운 타로를 주세요
Next time
다음번에
I’ll bake it for you if I get the chance
기회가 된다면 구워드릴께요
It makes me a little hungry
조금 배가 고프네요
Let’s take you to eat
식사에 데려가세요
This wonton tastes really good
이 완탕은 정말 맛있어요
Thank you, little lady
고맙습니다, 아가씨
This is my homemade bone broth
이것은 제가 직접 만든 사골육수입니다
So it tastes very good
맛이 너무 좋아요
Store
스토어
Business is good tonight
오늘 밤 사업은 좋습니다
There aren’t many people around now
지금은 사람이 많지 않아요
Everyone crowded to see
모두가 보기 위해 붐볐습니다
Kill Han Li
한리 살해
Beheading
참수
The original one was killed
원본은 사망했습니다
Awesome
굉장해요
Where is Mr. Han in Yizhou City
이저우시 한씨는 어디에 있나요
Kill him, kill him, kill him
죽여라, 죽여라, 죽여라
Master
마스터
Everything has been arranged
모든 것이 준비되었습니다
The time is up
시간이 다 됐어요
Kill Han Li to sacrifice to the river god
강의 신에게 제물로 바치기 위해 한리(Han Li)를 죽여
The Savior
구세주
走
설명
Two two persons
두 명
Take a look at our wristbands
팔찌 살펴보기
This is the finest buffalo leather
이것은 최고급 버팔로 가죽입니다
My wife is a needle and a thread
내 아내는 바늘과 실이다
sewn
꿰매
Three layers of leather are particularly strong
세 겹의 가죽이 특히 강함
Master
마스터
Are you an archer?
당신은 궁수인가요?
It’s perfect to wear it
입기 딱 좋아요
Not bad
나쁘지 않습니다
Little Lady
작은 아가씨
Buy one for your husband
남편을 위해 하나 구입
I fixed the windmill for you
내가 당신을 위해 풍차를 고쳐 주었습니다
Should you
해야 할까요
Give me something
뭔가를 주세요
He is not my husband
그 사람은 내 남편이 아닙니다
這
這
Obviously a good match
분명히 좋은 경기입니다
Am I wrong?
제가 틀렸나요?
Store
스토어
What was that young man asking just now
방금 그 청년이 무엇을 묻고 있었나요
Wrist guards
손목 보호대
I asked but didn’t buy it
문의했지만 구매하지 않았습니다
I don’t know what I’m thinking
내가 무슨 생각을 하는지 모르겠어요
It seems that the emperor and his grandson have left no stone unturned
황제와 그의 손자는 모든 것을 돌보지 않은 것 같습니다
A big show has been arranged separately
큰 쇼가 별도로 마련되었습니다
He Xiaowei, you praise me so much
샤오웨이님, 저를 너무 칭찬해주시네요
I always feel like I have a plan
항상 계획이 있는 것 같아요
Not thorough enough
충분히 철저하지 않음
Laolan River Shibawan
라오란 강 시바완
The first bay is the Silver Pine Beach
첫 번째 만은 실버 파인 비치입니다
Fish in Silver Pine Beach
실버 파인 비치의 물고기
Seventeen Lang Seventeen Lang
세븐틴랭 세븐틴랭
Ah Ying Shi Qi Lang Shi Qi Lang
아잉시치랑시치랑
How to make it like this
이렇게 만드는 방법
Nothing
아무것도 없음
Shichiro
시치로
How
방법
Kill what needs to be killed
죽여야 할 것을 죽이세요
Catch what needs to be caught
잡아야 할 것을 잡아라
No one left behind
아무도 남지 않았습니다
對
대
Where are the things
물건은 어디에 있나요
Lao Huang
라오 황
Take it out
꺼내세요
I found the tiger talisman
호랑이 부적을 찾았어요
Right here
바로 여기
These people
이 사람들
They are too stupid
그들은 너무 멍청해요
I don’t even know how to lure a snake out of its hole
뱀을 구멍 밖으로 유인하는 방법도 모르겠어요
It’s not that they are stupid
그들이 멍청해서가 아닙니다
That’s because Shichiro is too smart
그건 시치로가 너무 똑똑하기 때문이에요
Too stupid
너무 멍청하다
Too smart
너무 똑똑하다
It’s not that something is missing
뭔가 빠진 것은 아닙니다
Didn’t you put it in your arms
팔에 안넣었나요
You just said you wanted to borrow the Tiger Talisman
방금 호랑이 부적을 빌리고 싶다고 하셨습니다
Eliminate the murderous spirit
살인의 정신을 제거
Look for where to put it
어디에 놓을지 찾아보세요
Is the dick here with you
그 자지가 여기 당신과 함께 있나요?
No
아니요
Since you Cui Jiajun
최자준 이후
The mantis stalks the cicada and the oriole follows
사마귀가 매미를 따라가고 꾀꼬리가 따라옵니다
No need to hide it
숨길 필요가 없습니다
Chen Xing
첸 싱
Tiger Talisman Tiger Talisman
호랑이 부적 호랑이 부적
You stole our tiger charm
당신은 우리의 호랑이 부적을 훔쳤습니다
Hurry up and hand over the Tiger Talisman
서둘러 호랑이 부적을 건네주세요
Take it and return it to us
가져가서 저희에게 돌려주세요
You stole it
당신이 그것을 훔쳤습니다
Little Lady
작은 아가씨
Aren’t you the emperor’s grandson’s concubine
당신은 황제의 손자의 첩이 아닌가
Aren’t you going to elope with Shichiro?
시치로와 함께 도망치지 않겠습니까?
Although you are from the Cui family
당신은 Cui 가문 출신이지만
But not in Cao Ying
그러나 Cao Ying에서는 그렇지 않습니다
Is your heart in Han
당신의 마음은 한나라에 있나요
How to reverse it now
지금 되돌리는 방법
Help this pretty boy trick us
이 예쁜 소년이 우리를 속일 수 있도록 도와주세요
Just make it clear
명확하게 설명하세요
What's going on
무슨 일이야
Nonsense
말도 안되는 소리
You two are having trouble
두 분에게 문제가 있습니다
It won’t be such a big fuss
그렇게 큰 소란은 아닐 겁니다
Shut up
조용히
Li Huangsun
리황순
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻인가요?
How to speak to my subordinates
하급자와 대화하는 방법
I am your concubine
나는 당신의 첩입니다
How could you do this
어떻게 이런 일을 할 수 있었나요
Let them insult my Cui Jiajun
그들이 내 Cui Jiajun을 모욕하게 놔두세요
She said it herself
그녀가 직접 말했습니다
She told us personally
그녀가 직접 우리에게 말했습니다
Said she is the concubine of the emperor's grandson
그녀는 황제 손자의 첩이라고 말했습니다
I still want to follow us, Seventeen Lang
그래도 우리 세븐틴 랭을 팔로우하고 싶어요
Elopement
탈락
How could she help?
그녀가 어떻게 도와줄 수 있을까요?
You pretty boy
너 예쁜 소년
阿螢
阿螢
Master
마스터
I was in danger at the mountain village
산촌에서 위험에 빠졌어요
I just borrowed it
방금 빌렸어요
The identity of the royal family members
왕족의 정체성
These people don’t know what’s going on
이 사람들은 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는지 모릅니다
This is such a misunderstanding
이건 정말 오해입니다
He Xiaowei
허샤오웨이
Take a step to speak
말하기 위해 한 걸음 더 나아가세요
Let's go
가자
Don’t talk nonsense to him
그에게 말도 안되는 소리를 하지 마세요
Master
마스터
I'll be back soon
곧 돌아올게요
How did you guess it
어떻게 추측하셨나요
Your people these days
요즘 당신의 사람들
I almost turned over the Korean mansion
한국 맨션을 뒤집을뻔했어요
I knew it
알고 있었어요
Although you caught Han Li
한리를 잡았지만
But no tiger talisman was found
그러나 호랑이 부적은 발견되지 않았습니다
So you don’t have to work hard
그러니 열심히 일할 필요가 없습니다
Sohu Talisman
소후 부적
Han Li is suspicious and cunning
한리는 의심 많고 교활합니다
Since I didn’t carry it with me
내가 가지고 다니지 않았기 때문에
Looking through the entire Han Mansion again
한맨션 전체를 다시 둘러봅니다
Not found
찾을 수 없음
Then he must have put it in
그럼 그 사람이 그걸 넣었나 봐요
On my most trusted cronies
내가 가장 신뢰하는 동료들
And you spread the news
그리고 당신은 소식을 퍼뜨렸습니다
Pretend to kill Han Li again tonight
오늘 밤에도 한리를 죽이는 척
To lure the remnants of Han Li
한리의 잔당을 유인하기 위해
Come out to save people
사람들을 구하기 위해 나오세요
This move of yours lures the snake out of its hole
당신의 이러한 움직임은 뱀을 구멍 밖으로 유인합니다.
Really good
정말 좋아요
And you
그리고 당신
Just keep an eye on me
나를 지켜봐주세요
The mantis can catch the cicada
사마귀는 매미를 잡을 수 있습니다
The oriole is behind
꾀꼬리가 뒤에 있습니다
That's right
맞습니다
Then there is one more thing I don’t understand
그럼 제가 이해하지 못하는 것이 하나 더 있습니다
Promise me
약속해주세요
Invite to Chinese Valentine's Day
중국 발렌타인데이에 초대
It’s to enjoy the lanterns with me
저와 함께 등불을 즐기기 위해서입니다
To keep an eye on me personally
나를 개인적으로 지켜보기 위해
To avoid
피하려면
I found out that you have a secret plan
당신에게 비밀 계획이 있다는 걸 알아냈습니다
What about you
당신은 어떻습니까
Ask me out
나에게 물어보세요
What is it for
무엇을 위한 것인가요?
Come cruise with me
저와 함께 크루즈 여행을 떠나세요
Still don’t trust me
아직도 나를 믿지 마세요
Afraid that I might notice
내가 눈치챌까 두렵다
It will ruin things for you
당신의 일을 망칠 것입니다
each other
서로
Assignment
과제
Take a break
휴식을 취하세요
The Empress thought of a way
황후는 한 가지 방법을 생각했습니다
Let me leave the palace to practice Taoism
도교를 수행하기 위해 궁전을 떠나게 해주세요
I will arrange for you to hang out
당신이 어울릴 수 있도록 준비하겠습니다
Inside the palace maid accompanying the monk
스님과 동행하는 궁녀 내부
Come out of the palace with me
나와 함께 궁전에서 나가세요
Don’t be afraid
두려워하지 마세요
It should be just these days
요즘만 그래야 합니다
You can go out soon
곧 나가셔도 됩니다
Someone is coming
누군가 오고 있습니다
Take care when I leave
나가실 때 조심하세요
Ajie
아지
The Governor has given the order
지사가 명령을 내렸습니다
Let the female official beside Mrs. Xiao
샤오 부인 옆에 여성 공무원을 두세요
As a stand-in
대리인 역할
I left the palace to practice Buddhism
나는 불교를 수행하기 위해 궁궐을 떠났습니다
What
무엇을
Just let the female official out of the palace
그냥 여자 관리를 궁 밖으로 내보내주세요
What about that bitch Xiao
그 새끼 샤오는 어쩌고
Still safe and sound
여전히 안전하고 건전합니다
You are angry with me in this palace
당신은 이 궁전에서 나에게 화를 내고 있습니다
What's the matter with Sister?
수녀님에게 무슨 문제가 있나요?
Since the Governor has already
지사님이 이미
Infatuated with Xiao
샤오에게 푹 빠졌습니다
Then we have to do it step by step
그럼 단계별로 진행해야 합니다
As the saying goes
속담처럼
I can’t eat hot tofu in a hurry
급하게 뜨거운 두부를 먹을 수가 없어요
As long as we
우리가 있는 한
Put the wings around Xiao
샤오 주위에 날개를 달아주세요
They were all cut off by her
그들은 모두 그녀에 의해 끊어졌습니다
Are you still afraid that there is no way to kill her?
그녀를 죽일 방법이 없다는 사실이 아직도 두렵나요?
She is the late crown prince’s princess
고(故) 황태자의 공주
Collude with rebels
반군과 결탁
That's not
그렇지 않습니다
Obvious thing
분명한 사실
Ajie
아지
This is Xiao
샤오입니다
Just a bitch
그냥 개년
Infatuate the Governor
주지사의 마음을 사로잡다
It’s only temporary
일시적일 뿐입니다
Since she is so domineering
그녀는 너무 횡포하고 있기 때문에
Then I will naturally find a way to kill her
그러면 나는 자연스럽게 그녀를 죽일 방법을 찾게 될 것이다
Sister, don’t worry
자매님, 걱정하지 마세요
I will return to Luoyang immediately to supervise the battle
즉시 낙양으로 돌아가 전투를 감독하겠습니다
As long as our Yuan family is in front of the battle
우리 위안 가족이 전투 앞에 있는 한
Continue to make great contributions
계속해서 큰 기여를 해주세요
A sister is in Dadu
자매가 다두에 있어요
Place in mind
기억할 장소
It’s impregnable
난공불락입니다
Colonel
대령
This is my newly developed anesthetic
이것은 제가 새로 개발한 마취제입니다
Already painted on the arrow
화살표에는 이미 칠해져 있습니다
You try
해보시죠
Let me see
한번 볼까요
Miss
미스
When the emperor and grandson rescued you
황제와 손자가 당신을 구출했을 때
Just take off your robe
그냥 가운만 벗으세요
Put it on you
입어보세요
That action is so cool
그 행동은 정말 멋지네요
I was stunned upstairs
위층에서 깜짝 놀랐습니다
The emperor’s grandson promised us
황제의 손자가 우리에게 약속했습니다
Follow him
그를 팔로우하세요
In the future
향후
No more worries
더 이상 걱정하지 마세요
Thanks to the emperor’s grandson
황제의 손자에게 감사드립니다
Miss, are you talking about the emperor’s grandson
아씨, 황제의 손자 말씀하시는 겁니까
Would you like this leather wristband
이 가죽 팔찌를 원하시나요
He will definitely like it
그는 확실히 그것을 좋아할 것입니다
I only added a little bit of anesthetic
마취제만 조금 넣었어요
Meet He Xiaowei
허샤오웨이를 만나보세요
Miss Gu is so polite
구 선생님은 정말 예의바르세요
He Xiaowei’s smart outfit
허샤오웨이의 스마트한 의상
You are so handsome and handsome
당신은 정말 잘생겼고 잘생겼어요
Miss
미스
The emperor’s grandson asked us to wear men’s clothes
황제의 손자가 우리에게 남자 옷을 입으라고 했습니다
Follow the army
군대를 따라가세요
I see Captain He’s outfit
캡틴 히의 의상을 봅니다
Very beautiful
매우 아름답습니다
Miss, why don’t you ask Captain He for advice
미스, 캡틴 헤에게 조언을 구하는 게 어때요?
Cut it as you like
원하는 대로 잘라보세요
Talk
대화
He Xiaowei is in the army
샤오웨이는 군대에 있습니다
The courage gained through experience
경험을 통해 얻은 용기
So heroic
정말 영웅적이네요
Easy and good-looking
쉽고 보기에도 좋습니다
If I also wear this outfit
나도 이 옷을 입는다면
It’s just a painting of a tiger-like dog
호랑이 같은 개 그림일 뿐이에요
No problem
문제 없습니다
My clothes
내 옷
Taozi helped with the cooking
Taozi가 요리를 도왔습니다
You are not used to wearing men's clothing
당신은 남자 옷을 입는 것이 익숙하지 않습니다
Don’t know
모름
They actually sleeve this place
실제로 이곳을 소매하고 있습니다
It’s very big
매우 큽니다
And the shoulders and neck
어깨와 목
It’s also very generous
또한 매우 관대합니다
Men's clothing bought on the market
시중에서 구매한 남성복
Everything needs to be changed
모든 것이 바뀌어야 합니다
Peach
복숭아
Go back to the drawings we made
우리가 만든 그림으로 돌아가기
Send it to Miss Gu’s room
구씨 방으로 보내주세요
好
좋아
Thank you so much Captain He
대장님 정말 감사합니다
Miss Gu, you are welcome
구씨, 천만에요
Is this the dress
이게 드레스인가요
This is really a big deal
정말 큰일이네요
Not easy to cut
자르기가 쉽지 않음
No
아니요
This is the emperor's grandson
황제의 손자입니다
Lend our lady’s clothes
우리 부인의 옷을 빌려주세요
Our lady washed it with her own hands
우리 아줌마가 직접 손으로 씻었어요
I want to return it to the emperor’s grandson
황제의 손자에게 돌려주고 싶다
秋翠
특징
You talk too much
말을 너무 많이 하십니다
Actually
실제로
It was the emperor’s grandson who came to the rescue last time
지난번에 구조하러 온 것은 황제의 손자였습니다
I borrowed this coat
이 코트를 빌렸습니다
Cover for me
나를 대신해
He Xiaowei must not misunderstand
샤오웨이는 오해해서는 안 됩니다
Where
어디
Why did Miss Gu say this
구씨가 왜 이런 말을 했는지
So
그래서
I won’t delay Miss Gu
Miss Gu는 지체하지 않겠습니다
Colonel
대령
How do they talk
그들은 어떻게 대화하나요
Always taking some kind of detour
항상 어떤 종류의 우회로를 택함
Eighteen twists and turns
18개의 우여곡절
They are women in the boudoir
내실에 있는 여성입니다
Behave as you do
지금처럼 행동하세요
Naturally euphemistic and subtle
천연 완곡하고 미묘함
Okay, stop watching the excitement
좋아요, 흥분되는 모습을 그만 보세요
But they always mention the emperor’s grandson
그러나 그들은 항상 황제의 손자를 언급합니다
But the emperor’s grandson is with us
하지만 황제의 손자는 우리와 함께 있습니다
What does it matter
무엇이 중요합니까
What does it have to do with them
그것이 그들과 무슨 관련이 있나요
How do you know
어떻게 아시나요
The emperor’s grandson has nothing to do with them
황제의 손자는 그들과 아무 관련이 없습니다
Young master takes a look
젊은 스승님이 살펴보십니다
He is a person who is good at shooting
촬영을 잘하는 사람이에요
Put it on
입으세요
It couldn’t be more appropriate
이보다 더 적절할 수는 없습니다
Not bad
나쁘지 않습니다
Little Lady
작은 아가씨
Buy one for your husband
남편을 위해 하나 구입
I fixed the windmill for you
내가 당신을 위해 풍차를 고쳐 주었습니다
Should you
해야 할까요
Give me something
뭔가를 주세요
This Aying
이 아잉
It’s just a hard mouth but a soft heart
입은 딱딱하지만 마음은 부드럽습니다
So beautiful
너무 아름다워요
He Xiaowei
허샤오웨이
I have something to tell you
할 말이 있어요
Some people are
어떤 사람들은
So hard-spoken and soft-hearted
너무 딱딱하고 마음이 여린
I went out to work this morning
오늘 아침에 출근했어요
Don’t let me know either
저에게도 알리지 마세요
Really
정말
Obviously said not to send it
분명히 보내지 말라고 하더군요
Finally gave it away
드디어 기부했습니다
Looks like the person who gave the wristband to the emperor’s grandson
황제 손자에게 팔찌를 준 사람 같네요
The emperor and his grandson must have attached great importance to it
황제와 그의 손자는 이 일을 매우 중요하게 생각했을 것입니다.
Of course
물론이죠
It’s just my opinion
그냥 제 생각이에요
Although I value her
나는 그녀를 소중히 여기지만
But she
하지만 그녀는
But she values ​​me more
하지만 그녀는 나를 더 소중히 여깁니다
So
그래서
It’s time to congratulate the emperor’s grandson
황제의 손자를 축하할 시간입니다
What do you think
어떻게 생각하세요
The person who gave me the wristband
나에게 팔찌를 준 사람
Compared to my concubine
내 첩과 비교
How
방법
Emperor Sun Shenyan
순선옌 황제
I was trying to escape
탈출하려고 했어요
Expedient measures
신속한 조치
I just made this statement to deceive everyone
저는 모두를 속이려고 이런 말을 했을 뿐입니다
I didn’t expect the emperor’s grandson
황제의 손자는 기대하지 않았습니다
His articulation is frivolous
그의 표현은 경솔하다
Publicly in front of my young master
내 어린 스승님 앞에서 공개적으로
Insult my reputation
내 평판을 모욕합니다
I care so much about your son
나는 당신의 아들을 너무나 걱정하고 있습니다
That's natural
그건 당연합니다
Why
이유
It was not convenient for outsiders to know before
이전에는 외부인이 아는 것이 편리하지 않았습니다.
So I never told you
그래서 나는 당신에게 말한 적이 없습니다
Actually
실제로
I am the concubine of our young master
나는 우리 젊은 주인님의 첩입니다
So please be careful when speaking
그러므로 말할 때 조심하시기 바랍니다
Don’t do it again
다시는 하지 마세요
In front of my young master
어린 스승님 앞에서
Insulting my innocence
내 결백을 모욕하는 행위
Peach is gone
복숭아가 사라졌습니다
Colonel
대령
Why did you tell the emperor?
왜 황제에게 알렸나요?
You are the young master’s concubine
당신은 젊은 주인의 첩입니다
Today’s negotiations are reaching a critical point
오늘 협상은 중요한 지점에 도달했습니다
If you want to mess with him
그 사람을 괴롭히고 싶다면
Li Huangsun’s mind
이황순의 마음
Must have one
반드시 있어야 합니다
Unexpected news is good
예상치 못한 소식이 좋다
You have to say this to disturb his mind
그 사람의 마음을 어지럽히려면 이렇게 말해야 합니다
That’s not damaging
해롭지는 않습니다
Does your daughter’s family have a good reputation?
딸의 가족은 평판이 좋나요?
Between you and the young master
당신과 젊은 스승 사이
Innocent
무죄
Obviously not at all
전혀 그렇지 않습니다
Not his concubine
그의 첩이 아님
This is how you talk about yourself to outsiders
외부인에게 자신에 대해 이야기하는 방법
Do you want to get married in the future
앞으로 결혼하고 싶나요
Silly girl
멍청한 소녀
The man who can marry me in this world
이 세상에서 나와 결혼할 수 있는 남자
You don’t mind if I say that
내가 그렇게 말해도 괜찮습니다
That’s not right
그렇지 않습니다
You always said before
당신은 전에도 항상 말했어요
The man who can marry you in this world
이 세상에서 당신과 결혼할 수 있는 남자
I'm afraid I haven't been born yet
아직 태어나지도 않았네요
Why did you suddenly change your mind today
오늘 왜 갑자기 마음이 바뀌었나요
You finally discovered the world
드디어 세상을 발견했습니다
There is a man who can marry you
당신과 결혼할 수 있는 남자가 있습니다
Isn’t it
그렇지 않나요
Tell me who it is
누구인지 말해주세요
He is
그는
I won’t tell you
말하지 않겠습니다
Let’s go quickly
빨리 가자
Tell me
말해 보세요
I want to know
알고 싶습니다
Jianzhou defenders recognized talismans but not people
Jianzhou 수비수들은 부적을 인식했지만 사람은 인식하지 못했습니다.
Our Cui Jiajun
우리 최자준
Now that the tiger talisman is in hand
이제 호랑이 부적을 손에 넣었습니다
Jianzhou is already ours
Jianzhou는 이미 우리의 것입니다
Then you should take the Tiger Talisman
그렇다면 호랑이 부적을 가져가세요
Don’t think I don’t know
모른다고 생각하지 마세요
Don’t you just want Han Li
한리만 원하는 게 아닌가요
Enter the city with the Tiger Talisman
호랑이 부적을 가지고 도시에 들어가세요
Threaten Han Li
한리를 위협
In this way, there will be no need to waste a single soldier
이렇게 하면 병사 한 명도 낭비할 필요가 없습니다
Capture Jianzhou City
젠저우시 점령
Yizhou City is already yours
이저우 시는 이미 당신의 것입니다
What is the use of holding on to Han Li
한리를 붙잡아도 무슨 소용이 있나요
Then you should steal the military rations
그럼 군량량을 훔쳐야지
Give them all back to our Zhenxi Army
모두 우리 진시군에게 돌려주세요
There should be a result today
오늘 결과가 나올 겁니다
I’m afraid it’s the grandson of the emperor
유감이지만 황제의 손자
Not that easy to talk to
대화하기가 쉽지 않음
Han Li
한리
I want to order
주문하고 싶습니다
Master
마스터
Your hair is loose
머리카락이 느슨해졌습니다
Let me help you comb it
빗질을 도와드리겠습니다
好
좋아
Shichiro
시치로
Actually about
실제로는
He Xiaowei of Cui Jiajun
Cui Jiajun의 허샤오웨이
There is a saying
라는 말이 있습니다
I don’t know whether to say it or not
말해야 할지 말아야 할지 모르겠습니다
Improper
부적절
好
좋아
Our young master said it
우리 젊은 스승님이 말씀하셨어요
We have been talking for several days
우리는 며칠 동안 이야기를 나눴습니다
According to the old covenant
옛 언약에 따르면
This Han Li was captured by the Zhenxi Army
이 한리는 진시군에게 포로가 되었습니다
Nayizhou City
나이저우시
It will be owned by Zhenxi Army
진시군이 소유하게 됩니다
But this is the tiger symbol
하지만 이것은 호랑이 상징입니다
Acquired by our Cui Jiajun
Cui Jiajun이 인수
This is Jianzhou City
여기는 젠저우시입니다
It should belong to our Cui family army
우리 추이 가문 군대에 속해야 합니다
The tiger talisman is obviously us
호랑이 부적은 분명 우리입니다
Found first
먼저 찾았습니다
You took it away by trickery
당신은 속임수로 그것을 빼앗아갔습니다
And Yizhou City
그리고 이저우시
Obviously it belongs to our Zhenxi Army
분명히 우리 진시군 소속입니다
You entered the city first
당신이 먼저 도시에 들어왔습니다
Steal food and grass
음식과 풀을 훔치세요
Return the food and grass first
음식과 풀을 먼저 반납하세요
Let’s talk about Jianzhou
젠저우(Jianzhou)에 대해 이야기해보자
This is it
이것이 바로
It’s better for everyone to stay calm
모두가 침착하게 지내는 것이 좋습니다
Discuss it carefully
신중하게 논의하세요
Speaking is better than singing
노래하는 것보다 말하는 것이 좋습니다
What discussion
어떤 토론
That’s what you want
당신이 원하는 게 바로 그것입니다
Take advantage of our Zhenxi Army
진시군을 활용하세요
This warrior
이 전사
You can’t say that
그렇게 말하면 안 돼요
Since it is a discussion
토론이므로
Then give in at a loss
그럼 포기하고 포기하세요
Our Cui Jiajun
우리 최자준
Everything is possible
모든 것이 가능합니다
行
행
Then tell me
그럼 말해 보세요
How do you plan to suffer a loss
어떻게 손실을 입을 계획인가요?
His Royal Highness Didn’t Want to
전하는 원하지 않았습니다
Help the country to fall
국가가 몰락하도록 도와주세요
Recover the Eastern and Western Capitals
동서양 수도 회복
You can suppress the Western Army
서부군을 제압할 수 있습니다
Current grain storage
현재 곡물 저장 공간
Don’t talk about recovering both the east and west
동쪽과 서쪽을 모두 회복하는 것에 대해 이야기하지 마십시오
I’m afraid it’s even the edge of the Luo River
아쉽게도 낙강 가장자리까지
Can’t even touch it
만질 수도 없어요
If you are in Yizhou
이저우에 계시다면
Delay for a few more days
며칠 더 지연
I'm afraid this food reserve will become increasingly insufficient
이 식량 비축량은 점점 부족해질 것 같습니다
Now you and I have two armies
이제 당신과 나에게는 두 개의 군대가 있습니다
On the issue of statehood
국가 지위 문제에 대하여
Always arguing
항상 논쟁
But follow the rules
규칙을 따르세요
This Tiger Talisman
이 호랑이 부적
Since already
이미
Acquired by our Cui Jiajun
Cui Jiajun이 인수
Then Jianzhou City
그 다음에는 젠저우시
It should belong to our Cui family army
우리 추이 가문 군대에 속해야 합니다
It’s just that we want to ask Han Li
한리에게 묻고 싶은 것입니다
For convenience
편의를 위해
So our young master
그래서 우리 젊은 스승님
I just said
방금 말했어요
We plan to suffer some losses
약간의 손실을 입을 계획입니다
I will give you fifty carts of food and grass
내가 너에게 음식과 풀이 담긴 수레 50개를 주겠다
This can also help you
이 또한 도움이 될 수 있습니다
Leave camp and head to Luoyang as soon as possible
캠프를 떠나 가능한 한 빨리 뤄양으로 가세요
With the bravery of your army
당신 군대의 용기로
Are you still afraid that you won’t be able to defeat Luoyang?
낙양을 이길 수 없을까 봐 아직도 두렵나요?
That’s what you said
그렇게 말씀하셨습니다
Feel like we
우리 같은 느낌
Got a big deal
큰일 났어요
Fifty carts of grain and grass
곡식과 풀 50수레
A mere fifty loads of grain and grass
곡물과 풀이 고작 50가량
Only enough for us to suppress the Western Army
서방군을 제압할 만큼만
Two meals a day
하루 두 끼
Reluctantly arrived at the bank of Luo River
마지못해 뤄강둑에 도착
Which one is more important, Jianzhou or Luoyang
젠저우(Jianzhou)와 뤄양(Luoyang) 중 어느 것이 더 중요합니까?
His Royal Highness the Imperial Sun
황제의 태양 전하
You can’t tell the difference
차이를 구분할 수 없습니다
Natural
자연
Would the emperor be willing to use Han Li
황제가 한리를 기꺼이 이용하시겠습니까
In exchange for fifty loads of food and grass
음식과 풀 50개를 대가로
Yes
예
Seventeen Lang Seventeen Lang
세븐틴랭 세븐틴랭
好
좋아
His Royal Highness the Imperial Sun
황제의 태양 전하
Nature is a promise
자연은 약속입니다
As long as you take Han Li down
한리를 쓰러뜨리기만 한다면
Leave it to us Cui Jiajun
최자준에게 맡겨주세요
Then our young master
그럼 우리 젊은 스승님
I will never break my promise
나는 결코 약속을 어기지 않을 것이다
Food and grass will be delivered on time
음식과 잔디는 정시에 배달됩니다.
Seventeen Lang Seventeen Lang
세븐틴랭 세븐틴랭
These fifty cars are too few
이 50대의 자동차는 너무 적습니다.
Old Bao
올드바오
Please leave me alone
나를 내버려두세요
Tell me
말해 보세요
What's the plan
계획은 무엇입니까
What kind of plan
어떤 계획
Didn’t you agree on purpose
일부러 동의한 것이 아닌가요
That Captain He
그 선장
Exchange Han Li for fifty carts of grain and grass
한리를 곡식과 ​​풀 수레 50개로 교환
Are you planning to kill three birds with one stone
일석이조
Taking advantage of the Cui family's unpreparedness
Cui 가족의 준비되지 않은 점 이용
Capture Liangcao and Han Li together
량차오와 한리를 함께 포획
By the way, capture Jianzhou again
그런데 다시 Jianzhou를 점령하세요
Han Li has both grain and grass
한리는 곡식과 풀을 모두 가지고 있습니다
And win Jianzhou
그리고 Jianzhou에서 승리하세요
Is there any good way
좋은 방법이 있나요
Not now
지금은 아님
You are confident
당신은 자신감이 있습니다
Has it been planned in advance
미리 계획되었나요
Why don't you
당신은 왜
I agreed so easily
너무 쉽게 동의했습니다
That Captain He
그 선장
Such harsh conditions
이런 가혹한 조건
I have a friend
친구가 있어요
My friend
내 친구
He fell in love with a girl
그는 여자와 사랑에 빠졌습니다
Wait until the Zhenxi Army hands over Han Li
진시군이 한리를 넘겨줄 때까지 기다리세요
Ask Zuo Ying to take Han Li and Tiger Talisman
Zuo Ying에게 Han Li와 Tiger Talisman을 가져가라고 요청하세요
Leave camp immediately
즉시 캠프를 떠나세요
Go to recover Jianzhou
젠저우를 회복하러 가세요
I'd better go there myself
내가 직접 거기로 가는 게 좋겠다
No need
필요 없음
Now we have Han Li and Tiger Talisman
이제 Han Li와 Tiger Talisman이 생겼습니다
Jianzhou City must be easily captured
Jianzhou시는 쉽게 점령되어야 합니다
Now in Luoyang instead
지금은 뤄양에서
That’s the toughest part
가장 어려운 부분입니다
I guess Li Ni
Li Ni인 것 같아요
After getting the food and grass
음식과 풀을 얻은 후
It will definitely point directly at Luoyang
확실히 뤄양을 직접 가리키게 될 것입니다
We must be the first to do so
우리가 가장 먼저 그렇게 해야 합니다
His front
앞모습
What about your friend
당신의 친구는 어떻습니까
He is from our Zhenxi Army
그는 우리 진시군 출신입니다
I am still an old acquaintance of yours in Beijing
나는 아직도 베이징에서 당신과 오랜 지인입니다
Why are you shaking your head
왜 고개를 저으세요
Say it
말해 보세요
This girl
이 여자
He shouldn't like it
그는 그것을 좋아하지 않을 것입니다
Shouldn’t like
좋아하면 안 됨
Did he fall in love
그는 사랑에 빠졌나요
The Drunk Man in the Red Mansion
붉은 저택의 술 취한 남자
In fact, it doesn’t matter
사실 별거 아닙니다
As long as this poor man
이 불쌍한 사람이 있는 한
Good character
좋은 성격
It doesn’t matter
상관없어
No
아니요
What are you talking about
무슨 말을 하는 겁니까?
He finally fell in love with someone
그는 마침내 누군가와 사랑에 빠졌습니다
But that girl
근데 그 여자
Already someone else’s concubine
이미 다른 사람의 첩
Seventeen Lang, Seventeen Lang
세븐틴랭, 세븐틴랭
I finally understand
드디어 이해했습니다
You are so unusual today
당신 오늘 정말 특이해요
Because of this
이 때문에
What is so abnormal
무엇이 그렇게 비정상적인가요
What's wrong with me
나한테 무슨 문제가 있는 걸까요
I’m talking about that friend
그 친구에 대해 말하는 것입니다
行
행
Let’s do it today
오늘 해보자
Tell me about your friend
당신의 친구에 대해 말해 보세요
National crisis is now at hand
국가적 위기가 눈앞에 다가왔습니다
He still thinks about little things about love
그는 여전히 사랑에 대한 사소한 생각을 하고 있습니다
He informed you of this
그가 당신에게 이 사실을 알렸습니다
It shows that he is deeply worried
심각한 걱정을 하고 있음을 보여줍니다
I will definitely continue to pester you in the future
앞으로도 계속 괴롭히겠습니다
Not really
그렇지 않습니다
Okay
알겠습니다
He knew that this man had a husband
그는 이 사람에게 남편이 있다는 것을 알고 있었습니다
Also secretly coveting
은밀히 탐내기도 합니다
Seventeen Lang, let me tell you
세븐틴랭, 알려드릴게요
Color makes the mind faint
색상은 정신을 희미하게 만듭니다
Actually
실제로
You don’t need to say anything
아무 말도 할 필요가 없습니다
Shichiro
시치로
I advise you to hurry up
서두르는 것이 좋습니다
Break it off with your friend
친구와 헤어져
Otherwise you are not afraid of being black if you are close to the ink
그렇지 않으면 잉크에 가까이 있으면 흑인이 되는 것을 두려워하지 않습니다
One day you will also like it
언젠가는 당신도 좋아하게 될 것입니다
Someone else’s concubine
다른 사람의 첩
Shichiro
시치로
Think twice
다시 생각해 보세요
Today Li Huangsun
오늘은 리황순
So lost
길을 잃었습니다
You agreed to us so easily
너무 쉽게 동의하셨네요
I don’t know what happened
무슨 일이 일어났는지 모르겠습니다
Who knows
누가 알겠어요
Then I will let Chen Xing
그럼 Chen Xing에게 허락하겠습니다
Going to arrange food and grass
음식과 잔디를 준비할 예정
Wait
잠깐
I thought of another plan
다른 계획을 생각했어요
If the time comes
때가 되면
Their people
그들의 사람들
Arrived in Luoyang before us
우리보다 먼저 뤄양에 도착했습니다
We ambush again
또 매복 공격을 가합니다
Then we can
그러면 할 수 있어요
The slave goes out of the palace to practice Taoism for the empress
노예는 황후를 위해 도교를 수행하기 위해 궁전 밖으로 나갑니다
It is the slave’s blessing
노예의 축복입니다
I am just a slave who has been serving the queen since childhood
저는 어려서부터 여왕님을 섬기던 노예일 뿐입니다
From the mansion
맨션에서
To the palace
궁전으로
So many years
수년
The slave is reluctant to leave
노예가 떠나기를 꺼려합니다
Empress’ future
황후의 미래
Take care
조심하세요
Practice is a good thing
연습은 좋은 것입니다
Gather blessings for me
나를 위한 축복을 모아주세요
Gather blessings for yourself
자신을 위한 축복을 모아보세요
I still have Jin Niang by my side
아직 내 곁에는 Jin Niang이 있습니다
Don’t worry
걱정하지 마세요
It’s you
당신이에요
Take care of yourself
몸조심하세요
Take care of Mrs. Jiang for me too
나를 위해서도 장여사를 돌봐주세요
Go ahead
계속하세요
是
是
Your Majesty, don’t worry
폐하, 걱정하지 마십시오
The slave is gone
노예가 사라졌습니다
Grand Governor
총재
It’s all done
모두 완료되었습니다
好
좋아
Go and talk to the lady
가서 그 여자에게 말을 걸어보세요
Just say
말해 보세요
I have taken it out on her behalf
내가 대신 가져왔습니다
Where is Concubine Xiao
샤오후궁은 어디에
In case you find out
알게 된 경우
She is a smart person
그녀는 똑똑한 사람입니다
I will definitely think
반드시 생각하겠습니다
It was sent by Zheng Guogong
Zheng Guogong이 보냈습니다
Kill those palace maids
궁녀들을 죽여보세요
Taking vent to Mrs. Wei
웨이 부인에게 화를 내는 것
But just in case Concubine Xiao can’t think about it
그러나 만일을 대비해 샤오후궁이 그것에 대해 생각할 수 없을 수도 있습니다
Refused to give up and got into a fight
포기하지 않고 싸웠습니다
Wouldn’t it be detrimental to Zheng Guogong
정궈공(Zheng Guogong)에게 해가 되지 않을까요
Just a few slaves
노예 몇 명
Kill, just kill
죽여라, 그냥 죽여라
I said it too
나도 말했어
She is a smart person
그녀는 똑똑한 사람입니다
She won’t do it because of them
그녀는 그들 때문에 그렇게 하지 않을 것입니다
Ignorance
무지
Strike an egg against a stone
돌에 계란을 부딪히세요
Emperor Sun Wei’s visit at night
쑨웨이 황제의 밤 방문
Do you want to be a gentleman
신사가 되고 싶나요
What are you here for?
당신은 무엇 때문에 여기에 있습니까?
I'm coming today
오늘 갈 예정입니다
I want to pay you back
갚고 싶습니다
What else can you give me
그 밖에 무엇을 주실 수 있나요
I came here to explain to you
나는 당신에게 설명하기 위해 여기에 왔습니다
I misunderstood during the day
낮에 오해했어요
I thought the wristband was a gift from you
팔찌는 당신이 주신 선물인 줄 알았어요
The words are offensive
말이 불쾌감을 줍니다
Please forgive me
용서해주세요
You thought it was from me
내가 보낸 줄 알았는데
是
是
I found out later
나중에 알았습니다
It was a gift from Miss Gu
구 선생님이 주신 선물이었습니다
But I have already removed the wrist guards
근데 손목 보호대를 이미 제거했어요
Give it back to her
그녀에게 돌려주세요
You thought it was from me
내가 보낸 줄 알았는데
So I like wearing it
그래서 입는 걸 좋아해요
Later I discovered
나중에 발견했습니다
It was a gift from Miss Gu
구 선생님이 주신 선물이었습니다
Give it back to her
그녀에게 돌려주세요
You want to tell me this
나에게 이 말을 하고 싶으신가요?
That's true
그렇습니다
Not really
그렇지 않습니다
This is not what I am
나는 그렇지 않다
Isn’t it just right for me to see the moonlight
달빛을 보는 게 딱 맞는 것 아닌가
Perfect for grabbing the Tiger Talisman
호랑이 부적을 잡기에 완벽
You guessed wrong this time
이번에는 추측이 틀렸습니다
The Tiger Talisman is not here
호랑이 부적은 여기에 없습니다
I know
알고 있어요
Since you know
아시다시피
Why are you still here
왜 아직 여기에 있나요
我
나
This is not what I am
나는 그렇지 않다
Colonel
대령
Are you asleep
자고 계시나요
I'm ready to sleep
잠잘 준비가 되었습니다
Then I’ll go to sleep too
그럼 나도 자러 갈게
Okay, go quickly
알겠습니다. 빨리 가세요
Then take a rest early, Captain
그럼 일찍 쉬세요, 함장님
Got it
확인
Why are you covering your eyes
왜 눈을 가리고 있나요
My face is so red
얼굴이 너무 빨개요
My wife, it’s hot here
아내님, 여기 더워요
It's windy and cold tonight
오늘 밤은 바람이 불고 추워요
The emperor’s grandson actually feels too hot
황제의 손자는 실제로 너무 더워요
You just
당신은 단지
Why do you need to cover it up for me
왜 나를 위해 덮어줘야 하나요
Trespassing into the woman’s bedroom late at night
늦은 밤에 여성의 침실에 무단 침입
The emperor and his grandson don’t mind the melon fields and plum blossoms
황제와 그의 손자는 참외밭과 매화를 좋아하지 않습니다
I still dislike it
아직도 싫어요
Let me tell you something serious
진지한 사실을 말씀드리겠습니다
Today you use fifty carts of grain and grass
오늘 당신은 곡식과 풀 수레 50개를 사용했습니다
It is obviously unfair to exchange for statehood
국가 지위를 바꾸는 것은 분명히 불공평합니다
I know your Cui family
나는 당신의 Cui 가족을 알고 있습니다
Manpower is lurking in Beijing
베이징에는 인력이 숨어있습니다
My father was detained in Beijing by Sun Jing
저의 아버지는 Sun Jing에 의해 베이징에 구금되었습니다
I would like to lend you a hand
도와드리고 싶습니다
Rescue my father
아버지를 구출하세요
The emperor is so rude
황제는 너무 무례해요
What if I don’t agree
동의하지 않으면 어떻게 되나요?
If you don’t agree
동의하지 않는 경우
Then I will
그럼 그럴게요
阿螢
阿螢
Are you asleep
자고 계시나요
I just fell asleep
방금 잠들었어요
I have something important to discuss with you
당신과 중요한 논의할 사항이 있습니다
Okay, here I come
알겠습니다. 제가 왔습니다
Master
마스터
Did the military newspaper come from somewhere?
군신문이 어딘가에서 나온 걸까요?
Actually, it’s nothing important
사실 별거 아닙니다
It’s just what I heard from Taozi
타오즈에게 들은 내용입니다
You haven’t had dinner
저녁을 먹지 않으셨습니다
That’s why I came to see you
그래서 당신을 만나러 왔습니다
But I see your complexion
하지만 당신의 안색을 보니
Pretty good
아주 좋습니다
It seems that I am worrying too much
너무 걱정이 많은 것 같습니다
But I had more snacks in the afternoon
하지만 오후에는 간식을 더 먹었습니다
I have no appetite at night
밤에 식욕이 없어요
Then go to bed early
그럼 일찍 자러
Young master, please rest early
젊은 스승님, 일찍 쉬세요
I’ve found out everything
모든 것을 알아냈습니다
The ashes of Mrs. Shen and Mrs. Jiang
쉔부인과 장부인의 유골
They were all thrown outside the city
그들은 모두 도시 밖으로 쫓겨났습니다
Look at her following me for a while
그녀가 나를 한동안 따라다니는 것 좀 보세요
But ended up with one
하지만 결국 한 가지로 끝났습니다
The end of a broken life
망가진 삶의 끝
Empress
황후
Cry if you want to
울고 싶으면 울으세요
I won’t cry
울지 않을 거예요
Being a Crown Princess
왕세녀 되기
I have to be strong and stop crying
힘내서 그만 울어야지
But I hate myself
하지만 난 내 자신이 싫어
Why is it so useless
왜 이렇게 쓸모없나요
Failed to save Jiang’s belly
장씨의 배를 구하지 못함
The prince’s flesh and blood
왕자의 살과 피
If one day I go underground
언젠가 지하로 간다면
The prince will never forgive me
왕자는 결코 나를 용서하지 않을 것이다
Empress
황후
The grandson is still alive
손자가 아직 살아있습니다
If it weren’t for you
당신이 아니었다면
He won’t even survive now
그는 이제 살아남지 못할 것입니다
He is still waiting for you, Madam
그는 아직도 당신을 기다리고 있습니다, 부인
I know
알고 있어요
For the grandson
손자를 위해
I also want to live well
나도 잘 살고 싶다
The slave knows
노예는 알고 있습니다
The Empress bears the humiliation
황후는 굴욕을 감수합니다
For what
무엇을 위해
Mother Shen also knows
셴 어머니도 알고 계십니다
Tell the slave before she left
노예가 떠나기 전에 알려주십시오
She followed her empress to death without regret
후회 없이 죽음까지 황후를 따라간 그녀
Jin Niang too
진니앙도
Just a word from the queen
여왕의 한마디
Jin Niang died immediately
Jin Niang이 즉시 사망했습니다
Also happy
또한 행복합니다
Death without regrets
후회 없는 죽음
Empress
황후
Don’t talk about death easily
죽음에 대해 쉽게 이야기하지 마세요
Death is the easiest
죽음이 가장 쉽습니다
When the Prince passed away
왕자가 세상을 떠났을 때
If I take a knife and touch my neck
칼을 들고 목에 손을 대면
That’s the easiest
그게 가장 쉽죠
The world will still praise me for my steadfastness
세상은 여전히 ​​나의 확고함을 칭찬할 것입니다
But I understand in my heart
하지만 마음으로는 이해합니다
I can't do that
그렇게 할 수 없습니다
I have to survive
나는 살아남아야 한다
I want to do well
잘하고 싶어요
Dealing with Sun Jing
Sun Jing 상대하기
Maybe I can still find a chance
어쩌면 아직 기회가 있을지도 모릅니다
Keep your grandson
손자를 지키세요
I can still find opportunities to act by ear
아직도 귀로 행동할 기회를 찾을 수 있습니다
Help me recover the Dayu Dynasty
다유 왕조를 회복할 수 있도록 도와주세요
The empress feels bitter
황후는 괴로움을 느낀다
All slaves understand
모든 노예는 이해합니다
You said
당신이 말한 것
This child Xuanze
이 아이 Xuanze
Have you grown taller again
키가 또 컸나요
Han Chang took him to hide in Tibet
한창은 그를 티베트에 숨겨주었다
I don’t know about tonight either
저도 오늘 밤은 잘 모르겠습니다
Can you eat enough
충분히 먹을 수 있나요
Can you have a good sleep
푹 주무실 수 있나요
Your Highness
전하
Have a drink of water
물 한잔 마시세요
General Han
한 장군
Didn’t we discuss this before
이전에 이 문제를 논의하지 않았나요
Are you traveling disguised as your uncle or nephew?
삼촌이나 조카로 변장하여 여행하시나요?
General, just call me Aze
장군님, 그냥 아제라고 불러주세요
The grandson’s identity is different
손자의 신원이 다릅니다
No one is around here
여기에는 아무도 없습니다
Etiquette to be observed
준수해야 할 에티켓
You should still keep it
계속 보관해야 합니다
Are you hungry, Your Highness?
배고프신가요, 폐하?
Not hungry
배고프지 않아요
General Han
한 장군
Has there been any news from the concubine
첩에게서 소식이 있었나요
No
아니요
來
예
The Crown Princess has a strong heart
왕세녀는 강한 마음을 가지고 있습니다
Endure the humiliation
치욕을 참아보세요
If it weren’t for her clever arrangement
그녀의 영리한 배치가 아니었다면
My grandson and I
손자와 나
It’s hard to escape Sun Jing’s arrest
Sun Jing의 체포를 피하기는 어렵습니다
It’s a long journey now
지금은 긴 여정입니다
Intermittent news from the Crown Princess
왕세자빈의 간헐적인 소식
This is also common
이것도 흔한 일입니다
I hope my mother and concubine will be safe and sound
저의 어머니와 첩이 무사하길 바랍니다
Met the emperor’s grandson
황제의 손자를 만나다
I don’t know why the emperor and grandson invited him
황제와 손자가 왜 그를 초대했는지 모르겠습니다
Together in this Yizhou City
이 저우시에서 함께
Military Disturbance
군사적 소요
I haven’t had a word with the young master yet
아직 젊은 스승님과 아무 말도 나누지 못했습니다
I prepared some wine today
오늘은 와인을 준비했어요
I would like to treat you to a few drinks
당신에게 음료수 몇 잔을 대접하고 싶습니다
I never drink alcohol
나는 술을 마시지 않는다
I have something to ask for
부탁할 것이 있습니다
Please give me some thin noodles, sir
가는 국수 좀 주세요
The emperor’s grandson is in trouble
황제의 손자가 곤경에 빠졌습니다
Just say it
말해 보세요
I didn’t know Captain He’s identity before
저는 이전에 Captain He의 정체를 몰랐습니다
If any offense
위법 행위가 있는 경우
I hope you will forgive me
용서해주시기 바랍니다
What identity
어떤 정체성
Her identity
그녀의 정체성
Master
마스터
Why ask even though you already know
이미 알고 있는데 왜 물어보세요
She is no more than our military captain
그녀는 우리 군 대장에 불과합니다
What identity can it have
어떤 정체성을 가질 수 있나요
Young master, you don’t have to hide
젊은 스승님, 숨지 않으셔도 됩니다
I already know everything
나는 이미 모든 것을 알고 있습니다
As long as the young master agrees
젊은 주인이 동의하는 한
Do me this favor
이 부탁을 들어주세요
I will keep this secret
이 비밀은 비밀로 하겠습니다
Never let others know
다른 사람에게 알리지 마세요
Don’t worry, sir
걱정하지 마세요, 선생님
I, Li Shiqi, have said it all
나 Li Shiqi가 모든 것을 말했습니다
A horse is hard to catch
말은 잡기 어렵습니다
As long as the young master agrees
젊은 주인이 동의하는 한
I will keep this a secret
이건 비밀로 하겠습니다
Rotten in the stomach
위가 썩음
You don’t want to kill me to silence me
당신은 나를 침묵시키기 위해 나를 죽이고 싶지 않습니다
Master
마스터
Although your Cui family army is powerful
당신의 Cui 가족 군대는 강력하지만
But our Zhenxi Army is also in Yizhou
하지만 우리 진희군은 이저우에도 있습니다
Can the young master succeed
젊은 스승은 성공할 수 있을까
The emperor and his grandson were joking
황제와 그의 손자는 농담을 하고 있었습니다
Everyone is the master of diligence
모든 사람은 근면의 달인입니다
The emperor and grandson tell me
황제와 손자가 나에게 말했다
What's the matter with you
무슨 일이 있으신가요?
Need help from our Cui family
Cui 가족의 도움이 필요합니다
But it doesn’t matter
그러나 그것은 중요하지 않습니다
My father, King Liang
나의 아버지, 양왕
Detained in Beijing by Sun Jing
Sun Jing에 의해 베이징에서 구금
I know your Cui family
나는 당신의 Cui 가족을 알고 있습니다
There are experts lurking in Beijing
베이징에는 전문가가 숨어있습니다
As long as the young master can help me
젊은 스승님이 나를 도와줄 수만 있다면
I will be able to rescue my father
나는 아버지를 구출할 수 있을 것이다
Master
마스터
The captain asked
선장이 물었다
Just know
알아두세요
You are coming to the emperor’s grandson
당신은 황제의 손자를 만나러 갑니다
It’s time for you to go back and take your medicine
이제 돌아가서 약을 드실 시간입니다
I say Shikiro
시키로라고 해요
You don’t say
당신은 말하지 않습니다
Are we going to have a Hongmen Banquet today
오늘은 홍문 연회를 할까요
Why is it finished so quickly
왜 이렇게 빨리 끝나나요
You said
당신이 말한 것
This Mr. Cui
이 Mr. Cui
What kind of person is he?
그 사람은 어떤 사람인가요?
Looking polite
예의바른 모습
Like a young man
젊은 남자처럼
It really doesn’t look like it
정말 아닌 것 같습니다
A person who can lead troops to fight
군대를 이끌고 싸울 수 있는 사람
Yeah
예
He is such a person
그 사람은 그런 사람이에요
A quiet and weak person
조용하고 약한 사람
You can actually get here from Yingzhou
실제로 잉저우(Yingzhou)에서 여기로 올 수 있습니다
Conquered so many cities
너무나 많은 도시를 정복했습니다
Do you think this is strange
이상하다고 생각하시나요
Cui Yi’s son
최이의 아들
It shouldn’t be bad
나쁘지 않아야 합니다
Who is Cui Yina
추이이나는 누구인가
The famous general of the day
당대의 유명한 장군
With General Sun Jingpei
손징페이 장군과 함께
Earlier they were also known as the Three Heroes of the Kingdom
이전에는 그들은 왕국의 세 영웅으로도 알려졌습니다.
Then tell me
그럼 말해 보세요
What kind of person is He Xiaowei
허샤오웨이는 어떤 사람인가요
This
이것
I really can’t see through this
이건 정말 꿰뚫어 볼 수가 없어요
You know
알고 계시죠
I have been fighting in the battlefield for more than ten years
나는 10년 넘게 전장에서 싸워왔습니다
What kind of person have I never seen
나는 어떤 사람을 본 적이 없나요
But such a person
근데 그런 사람
I’ve never seen it before
한 번도 본 적이 없습니다
You said she is a woman
당신은 그 사람이 여자라고 했어요
She is cruel and quick
그녀는 잔인하고 빠르다
Extremely resourceful
매우 능숙함
I really can’t figure it out
정말 모르겠어요
So I always feel
그래서 저는 항상 느낍니다
This Captain He’s identity is not simple
이 선장의 정체는 간단하지 않습니다
Every word she said
그녀가 말한 모든 단어
I don’t know how much I can believe it
얼마나 믿을 수 있을지 모르겠습니다
Right
그렇습니다
Shichiro
시치로
The army is ready to march
군대가 행진할 준비가 되었습니다
Our defense in Yizhou
이저우에서의 우리 방어
Also prepared
또한 준비됨
When are you leaving
언제 떠나시나요
The sooner the better
빠를수록 좋습니다
Colonel
대령
When I rush there
내가 달려갈 때
The young master looks very ugly
젊은 주인이 너무 못생겼어요
No problem
문제 없습니다
The young master has already told what Li Ni said
젊은 스승은 이미 Li Ni가 말한 것을 말했습니다
Tell me everything
모든 것을 말해 보세요
Li Yi is a killer
리 이(Li Yi)는 살인자입니다
He actually said blackmail
그는 실제로 협박을 했다고 합니다
Want to kill two birds with one stone
일석이조
I want to deceive my true identity
본인의 정체를 속이고 싶습니다
I want to trick the young master into agreeing to him again
젊은 스승을 속여 다시 그의 말에 동의하게 만들고 싶습니다
Rescue King Liang
량왕 구출
Fortunately, the young master was not fooled
다행히 젊은 스승은 속지 않았습니다
But this is Li Ni
근데 이게 리니예요
Already starting to get suspicious
이미 의심스럽기 시작했습니다
Fortunately, you have persuaded the young master
다행히 젊은 스승님을 설득하셨습니다
Start the Chen Bing Luo River early
Chen Bing Luo River를 일찍 시작하십시오
What's here
여기에는 무엇이 있나요
Let me clean up first
먼저 정리하겠습니다
Colonel
대령
Shall we take this windmill with us
이 풍차를 가지고 갈까요
Throw it away
버리세요
Really threw it away
정말로 버렸어요